<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
		<name>Armors</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="">Seiliu</author>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="items-gear.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Seiliu/beefers-items/main/items-gear.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Floating Board" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_FLOATINGBOARD">
        <description>
            <p>A magical board that allows the user to float just above the ground. </p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increases speed to 70 feet when ridden.</li>
                <li>When mounted, removes the ability to disengage.</li>
                <li>Equipping takes one action.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
            <set name="slot">mount</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                <p>A magical board that allows the user to float just above the ground.</p>
                <b>Removes the ability to disengage and takes a full action to to equip and unequip.</b>
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
        <element name="Terrifying Biomass" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_TERRIFYINGBIOMASS">
        <description>
            <p>A strange lump of meat. It is teeming with magical energy.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>During battle, the biomass can be molded into any shape that it's owner wishes, whether it be a physical weapon or a ranged weapon.</li>
                <li>Any weapons created from this item have damage dice in a range of <b>1d10-3d6</b>.</li>
                <li>At the cost of losing your bonus action, you can add your weapon modifier to the attack.</li>
                <li>If the owner loses an appendage, the biomass will mold itself into the shape of that appendage unless prompted otherwise. This gives advantage on biomass attack.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                <p>During battle, the biomass can be molded into any shape that it's owner wishes. Any weapons created from this item have damage dice in a range of <b>1d10-3d6</b>. At the cost of losing your bonus action, you can add your weapon modifier to the attack. If the owner loses an appendage, the biomass will mold itself into the shape of that appendage unless prompted otherwise. This gives advantage on biomass attack.</p>
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Void" type="Magic Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_VOIDRING">
        <description>
            <p>Obtain the ability to turn invisible until the end of your next turn. While invisible, you can sneak attack instead of regularly attacking. You are considered invincible until you are found/noticed, or until you exit invisibility.</p>
            <p>This ability can only be used twice per combat.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Spine of Time" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_TIMESPINE">
        <description>
            <p>A medically induced magic item that only the best of the best assassins can obtain and have put into their body.</p> 
            <p>Upon having this placed into you, you lose 5 hp. As a bonus action you can activate the spine and you choose one of the following abilities to keep when first usage:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><p><i>Quick Feet-</i> As a bonus action, move an extra 40ft and obtain a level of exhaustion</p></li>
                <li><p><i>Double Take-</i> As a bonus action, you can move out of enemies attack range without triggering an attack of opportunity. Obtain one level of exhaustion.</p></li>
                <li><p><i>Left and Right-</i>  As a bonus action, you can attack a second time with an offhand weapon. Upon usage, you obtain two levels of exhaustion, and you cannot move on your next turn.</p></li>
                <li><p><i>EMP-</i> As an action, you can spend all of your blood and energy to send out an emp in a 20 foot radius of yourself. Enemies are stopped from using special abilities and may only use a weapon attack.</p></li> 
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="hp" value="-5" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Top Hat of Gien" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_GIENTOPHAT">
        <description>
            <ul>
                <li><p><i>Gifted Speech-</i> While attuned to this item, you have +3 Charisma.</p></li>
                <li><p><i>Mercie's Gift-</i> You may use a reaction to heal an ally within 15 feet of yourself for [2d6+level]</p></li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
            <set name="slot">head</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_CLASS_FEATURE_TOPHATGIEN_MERCIESGIFT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Six Eyes" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_SIXEYES">
        <description>
        <p>Upon entering combat with an enemy, you may learn <b>1d2</b> of its abilities.</p>
        <p>You have advantage on martial checks.</p>
        <p>Upon death, you find the strength within these eyes to temporarily invigorate yourself and return to the fight. You are alive for three turns; if you do not deal enough damage (determined by DM) by the end of your third turn, you will fall unconscious once more.</p>
        <p><i>This item can be forcibly unattuned.</i></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
            <set name="slot">sixeyes</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intimidation" value="3" />
            <stat name="insight" value="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Tiamat's Essence" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_TIAMATESSENCE">
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <ul>
                <li>When a creature attunes to this item, the eye must stay covered unless the creature’s fate is tied with it.</li>
                <li>Upon attunement, the creature may reveal the eye as a bonus action; the enemy must make a wisdom saving throw; upon failure, the targeted enemy has disadvantage on the next saving throw and your next hit will crit on an 18-20.</li>
                <li>The charges for this ability scales with proficiency and the eye's strength scales with your level.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
            <set name="slot">eye</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
            <stat name="strength" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="I Anatomically Heart U" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_IHEARTU">
        <description>
            <p>When successfully attacking an enemy, if your damage roll is even, charm them.</p>
            <p>Charmed enemies take an additional 1d6 damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
            <set name="slot">eye</set>
            <set name="attunement">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Wub" type="Item" source="Beefer's Items" id="ID_SEILIU_BEEFERSITEMS_ITEM_WUB">
        <description>
            <p>A ring with a nice message inside.</p>
            <p>All healing heals for an additional 1d4</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Beefer's Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="-">-</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="-">-</set>
            <set name="slot">eye</set>
            <set name="attunement">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>
